simplesocialtools.com 2018-07-11

# Privacy Policy

**GDPR compliance**

The EU’s General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) took effect on May 25, 2018 and we are fully behind the spirit of these regulations for a safe and secure Internet. 

We collect basic contact information to allow you access to our membership site. Typically this will include contact details like full name, email addresses, payment methods, etc... in order to support membership login, content access and other account management functions. 

Overall, we aim for privacy by default: if data collection is not integral to the way our product works, then we won’t collect it. 

At any time, you may request your information to be exported and sent to you for review, and we promptly honor any requests by you to have your information deleted and forgotten. 

**Email Notifications:**

If you provide us with your email address or signup for our products and services, it will qualify you to receive emails from us about our products and services that you've signed up for, products, services or content we feel you may be interested in, occasional promotional emails, special discount offers and other important messages and announcements about our products and services. 

We respect your privacy. We will never sell, rent, lease or give away your information (name, address, email, etc.) to any third party. Nor will we send you unsolicited email. We'll only send you emails related to our products and services. 

But if you would like to unsubscribe from our email list and want to never hear from us again, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails and we’ll know that you're no longer interested in receiving emails from us. 

If you’d like to stay on our lists and continue getting emails from us about our products and services, no further action is required. 

**Use of Email Addresses and other Contact Information**

An important part of our services includes being able to provide information to you. As a result, you expressly consent to receiving communications from us via email, fax, telephone, mail, text, SMS, or any other delivery method, including to your cell phone, when you provide this information. 

As a customer you are agreeing to receive information about the product or service you purchased. This may include, but is not limited to, information about product or service updates, new features, or information we believe you may find interesting. 

We may also send you information about other products and services our company offers. 

We will not sell, provide, or transfer you email address to others. 

We may allow advertising to our customers, or engage in joint ventures, which result in your receiving advertisements from selected third parties. 

**General Privacy Policies**

We respect your interest in your privacy and as a result we have created this informational disclosure. 

We collect and use personal information for many purposes, including but not limited to, billing; product and service fulfillment; to better understand our customer needs; to provide a better website, products and services; to communicate with customers and potential customers regarding our products and services and third party products and services. 

Generally, your private information will only be disclosed to our owners, employees, independent contractors, subsidiaries, partners, affiliates, attorneys, consultants, business associates, service providers, suppliers and agents, acting on our behalf or request. This general rule, and disclosures in specific situations, is more particularly described below. 

You must be at least 18 years old to access this website. We do not direct this website to persons under 18, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen. 

**Information Collected by our ISP**

The hosting provider for this Internet site (as with any Internet site) has the ability to record various information, including domain name, pages accessed, date and time of access, web browser type and computer operating system, and referring information, and to disclose this information. This is most commonly done by providing access to raw server logs. For more information you should perform an Internet search on 'server logs' or 'raw server logs.' We may have access to our raw server logs and access reports prepared by our hosting provider. 

**Financial Information for Billing Purposes**

We sell products and services. When sales are made financial information must be disclosed. This information can include any number of facts you are asked to provide, but most commonly includes your name, financial / credit card information, billing address, and email address. Generally, this purchase information will be provided by you to a third party payment processor and we do not receive your financial / credit card information. 

In the event we do receive financial / credit card information, we will not disclose it to anyone unless disclosure is required by law or a court order, or unless disclosure is required to address an issue implicated by the financial transaction. If you claim that your financial information was used to make a purchase you did not authorize, details about the financial transaction may be disclosed to law enforcement and anyone else we deem necessary to address the matter. 

**Identification of Purchasers**

If you purchase one of our products or services, you authorize us to use your name and identification information in advertising or promotions. 

We also use personal information in an aggregate form (i.e., not individually attributable to you) for business analysis, operational, marketing and other promotional purposes. 

You can access and change your personal information on the [Profile](http://simplesocialtools.com/profile) page at any time, after logging into your account. We will delete your account upon your request, when you [contact us](http://simplesocialtools.com/support). 

**Cookies and Tracking**

This website uses cookies to improve the user’s experience while visiting the website. 

Cookies are small text files saved to the user’s computer that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website. This enables the website to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website. 

Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website. 

Cookies may be used to keep track of referred affiliate commissions and to monitor access to our website. You consent to any future use of cookies for testing purposes and the use of cookies for publicly available data to gather statistics for the purpose of determining which search engines, referring sites, key words, etc., bring visitors to our website, which pages visitors are most interested in, what web browsers are used, etc. Various providers may be used for this purpose. The purpose is to obtain information that will help promote the website, make the website more interesting and useful to visitors, and to identify areas where improvement is needed. 

Our website does not respond to “do not track” requests from a web browser or other device, or other similar requests or procedures. 

Additionally, various third party information suppliers and other entities that provide information for this website, or for use by us, may use cookies. Examples include, but are not necessarily limited to billing providers, third party advertisers, and third party resources we promote. 

We may also allow third party advertisers to display ads on our website. We are not in a position to know if they collect identifiable information about an individual consumer’s online activities over time and across different websites, so you should assume they do. In most web browsers you can choose not to accept cookies from third party sites or third-party cookies. 

**Disclosure by Necessity**

Private information may be disclosed if required by a court order, statute, law, or regulation. 

Information is subject to disclosure to address a claim that you are violating the terms of any agreement pertaining to your use of your use this website or our products or services, or rights of any third party. 

Information is also subject to disclosure if we believe that disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring an action against someone who may be causing injury to or interfering (either intentionally or unintentionally) with our rights or property, your rights or property, other users of our website, products or services, or anyone else. 

As we continue to develop our business, we or our affiliates may sell or buy other businesses or entities, or we may merge with another company, or be bought by another company. In such transactions, personal information may be one of the transferred assets. 

Your information may be stored and processed in any country in which we maintain facilities or conduct operations. By using our website, products and services, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. 

After your account becomes inactive your information may remain in our databases, computers, and archives, and cannot reasonably be expunged. 

**Policy Changes**

These policies may be amended by us at any time and without notice, but will be posted at this page. 

You agree that your continued use of our websites, product or service after that date will constitute your consent and acceptance of the amendment. 

Effective Date: 05/25/2018
